--- Extracting from Visibility Graphs.pdf ---
--- Page 1 ---
RESEARCH ARTICLE
Visibility Graph Based Time Series Analysis
Mutua Stephen1,2, Changgui Gu1, Huijie Yang1*
1 Business School, University of Shanghai for Science and Technology, Shanghai 200093, China,
2 Computer Science Department, Masinde Muliro University of Science and Technology, P.O. Box 190-
50100, Kakamega, Kenya
* hjyang@ustc.edu.cn
Abstract
Network based time series analysis has made considerable achievements in the recent
years. By mapping mono/multivariate time series into networks, one can investigate both
itÆs microscopic and macroscopic behaviors. However, most proposed approaches lead to
the construction of static networks consequently providing limited information on evolution-
ary behaviors. In the present paper we propose a method called visibility graph based time
series analysis, in which series segments are mapped to visibility graphs as being descrip-
tions of the corresponding states and the successively occurring states are linked. This pro-
cedure converts a time series to a temporal network and at the same time a network of
networks. Findings from empirical records for stock markets in USA (S&P500 and Nasdaq)
and artificial series generated by means of fractional Gaussian motions show that the
method can provide us rich information benefiting short-term and long-term predictions.
Theoretically, we propose a method to investigate time series from the viewpoint of network
of networks.
Introduction
Complex network based time series analysis has attracted noteworthy attention in recent years
across various domains. By mapping a time series to a network, one can investigate visually the
structural patterns at different time scales from microscopic to macroscopic levels [ 1]. As a
result, several novel ways have been proposed on how to convert time series data into complex
networks. Zhang et al. [2û4] construct a network from pseudo periodic time series where each
cycle is represented by a single node, and a threshold is set to link node pairs with strong cross-
correlations. From the viewpoint of phase space reconstruction, one can also take all the possi-
ble series segments with a certain length as nodes. Xu et al propose an approach that links each
node with its closest k neighbors [5û8]. While in the references [ 9, 10] the nodes are networked
according to the correlation strength between the nodes, which turns out to be a special case of
the widely used recurrence network approach [ 11û24]. Lacasa et al propose the widely used vis-
ibility graph algorithms [25û35] by linking visible elements in a series. Each of these
approaches was quickly adopted and widely used among various researchers to extract infor-
mation embedded in time series from varied domains.
PLOS ONE | DOI:10.1371/journal.pone.0143015 November 16, 2015 1/1 9
a11111
OPEN ACCESS
Citation: Stephen M, Gu C, Yang H (2015) Visibility
Graph Based Time Series Analysis. PLoS ONE 10
(11): e0143015. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0143015
Editor: Zhong-Ke Gao, Tianjin University, CHINA
Received: June 23, 2015
Accepted: October 29, 2015
Published: November 16, 2015
Copyright: ⌐ 2015 Stephen et al. This is an open
access article distributed under the terms of the
Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits
unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any
medium, provided the original author and source are
credited.
Data Availability Statement: NASDAQ and SP 500
data are available from Yahoo Finance (http://finance.
yahoo.com/q/hp?s = \%5EGSPC+Historical+Prices).
Funding: The work is supported by the National
Science Foundation of China under Grant Nos
10975099 and 11505114, the Program for Professor
of Special Appointment (Orientational Scholar) at
Shanghai Institutions of Higher Learning under Grant
Nos D-USST02 and QD2015016, and the Shanghai
project for construction of discipline peaks. S. Mutua
acknowledges the financial support from Shanghai
Municipal Government under Scholarship No.
SH2013SLA004.
Competing Interests: The authors have declared
that no competing interests exist.
--- Page 2 ---
However, in the cited methods, a time series is projected to a static network. As a result, one
can hardly find the evolutionary behaviors of the system. A complicated system contains gener-
ally many elements, monitoring which produces a multivariate time series. In literature, several
novel methods are designed to extract from segments of the multivariate time series relation-
ship networks between the elements, as being the state representatives of the corresponding
time intervals. To cite examples, Munnix et al. [ 36] use the correlation matrix between stocks
to represent state of a stock market; In reference [ 37] Zheng, et al. employ the principal compo-
nent analysis to extract further believable information from the cross-correlation matrix; Gao
et al. [16, 17, 20, 21] embed a multivariate time series in a multi-dimensional phase space, and
calculate correlation between each pair of the phase tensors. Each segment of series corre-
sponding to each variate is mapped to a node. Strong relationships are reserved by introducing
different thresholds to filter out links between segments coming from the same series and from
different series, respectively. By this way, the recurrence network approach is extended to
investigate multivariate series; Buccheri et al. [ 38] construct from the correlation matrix the
plenary maximally filtered graphs (an extension of the simple spanning-tree), in which the
largest weights are retained while constraining the subgraph to be globally a planar graph;
While Gao [39, 40] conduct linear regressions of every element to other elements and the set of
values of fitting parameters are used to measure local states. The successive occurring states are
then linked into a transmission network.
The motivation of the present work is twofold. First, we try to find evolutionary behaviors
of a system embedded in one-dimensional time series. The existing algorithms to map a time
series to a network are generally designed in the framework of phase space reconstruction. For
a deterministic dynamical system, one can determine the embedding dimension of the system
m. All the segments with length m in the original time series are depicted in the phase space, as
being the states visited in the dynamical process. Every pair of states is linked if they are close
enough, which results into a network (e.g., recurrence network). But in the downstream proce-
dures of constructing networks, detailed information stored in the states is used in a rough
way. For example, in the recurrence plots one calculate the Euclidean distance between each
pair of the segments to measure the relationship between the states, in which the state informa-
tion is all lost except the distance. This roughness in using the information embedded in the
states covers up some interesting dynamical behaviors and this leads the focus only to the
global characteristics. Consequently, the states are not properly distinguished hence one cannot
monitor the systemÆs evolutionary behavior.
Quite often in practice, people are interested in the short-term prediction of a state. For
instance, one maybe interested in the present state of a stock, and its probable state in the fol-
lowing week. He may be concerned about the intensity of increase or decrease with reference to
historical data, an investigation that may not be obviously attained from literature review. This
guides our second motivation in this work in lieu of providing as concise as possible informa-
tion from a series segment (state).
In order to address the above stated motivations, we endeavor to extract state patterns con-
cisely while preserving the internal characteristics, and explore the transfer relations between
the distinguishable states. Contributions of the present work thus include,
We propose a method to construct a transmission network from a one-dimensional time
series, in which the nodes are the local states and the links the transfers between states. Techni-
cally, from an initial time series, one can extract all the segments in the series with a predefined
window size. We map each segment to a visibility graph, which is used to represent the state of
the system at the corresponding time interval. The successively occurring visibility graphs are
linked in turn, which leads to a transfer network of distinguishable states. The weights of links
Graph-Let Based Time Series Analysis
PLOS ONE | DOI:10.1371/journal.pone.0143015 November 16, 2015 2/1 9
--- Page 3 ---
Error reading Visibility Graphs.pdf: 'charmap' codec can't encode character '\u2212' in position 2623: character maps to <undefined>

==================================================

--- Extracting from Paper 2.pdf ---
--- Page 1 ---

--- Page 2 ---

--- Page 3 ---

--- Last Page ---


==================================================

--- Extracting from Time_Series_Analysis_Based_on_Visibility_Graph_Theory.pdf ---
--- Page 1 ---
Time Series Analysis based on Visibility Graph Theory  
 
Shijie Yan 
School of Automation and Electrical Engineering 
University of Science and Technology Beijing, 
 Beijing, China  
yanshijie0303@sina.com 
Danling Wang* 
School of Mathematics and Physics 
University of Science and Technology Beijing, 
 Beijing, China  
wang_dan_ling@sina.com
 
 
AbstractùThe dynamics of a complex system is usually 
recorded in the form of time series. In recent years, the 
visibility graph algorithm and the horizontal visibility graph 
algorithm have been recently introduced as the mapping 
between time series and complex networks. Transforming time 
series into the graphs, the algorithms allows applying the 
methods of graph theoretical tools for characterizing time 
series, opening the possibility of building fruitful connections 
between time series analysis, nonlinear dynamics, and graph 
theory. This paper analyzes mainly the topological properties 
of visibility graphs and horizontal visibility graphs associated 
to random series and fractional Brownian motions series, with 
a special emphasis on degree distribution of the associated 
graphs. As an example, this paper study the visibility graph 
and horizontal visibility graph constructed from the total daily 
turnover of stock market, and unveil that the degree 
distribution of visibility graph has power-law tails, and the 
degree distribution of horizontal visibility graph has 
exponential tail. 
Keywords-Time series analysis; Visibility graph; Horizontal 
Visibility Graph; Degree distribution; Daily turnover of stock. 
I.  INTRODUCTION  
Random graph theory is considered as basis of research 
on the topological structure of complex networks, however, 
most of real complex networks are not random graph. The 
structure of complex networks is irregularly, complex and 
always changing with time, thus when the research objects 
are changed from simple and small networks to complex 
networks with thousands of vertices and edges, researchers 
begin to focus on the integrally dynamical property in 
complex networks. In 1998, Watts and Strogatz [1] proposed 
the famous model of small world networks. In 1999, 
Barabßsi and Albert [2] build evolutionary model of scale 
free networks. These two great works bring the research of 
complex networks into a new age. Since the end of 20 th 
century, the researches and applications of complex 
networks have already spread to many fields, such as 
mathematics, biology, information sciences.  The 
understanding on the features of complex networks in 
quantities and qualities has become a hot and challenging 
issue at present [3-5]. 
In the research of complex networks, one of the most 
critical aims is designing an intuitional, simple and effective 
method to build the model of complex networks for certain 
research objects.  Since 2000, utilizing the analysis of 
topological structure to understand the dynamical behavior 
of time series via mapping them to complex networks has 
attracted researcherÆs great attention [6-10]. Zhang and Small 
[11,12] proposed an approach that map a time series to a 
cycle network. In this method, each vertex in network is a 
fragment in the time series. Edges between different vertices 
are determined by the similarity values or space distance of 
fragments. In 2008, Lacasa et al. [20] proposed the model of 
Visibility Graph (VG). In visibility graph, each vertex is 
each value in time series, edges between different vertices 
would exist if the two values can be ôseenö with each other. 
The visibility graph is suitable for all kind of time series and 
the networks retain the structure information of time series. 
Particularly, periodic sequence is mapped to regular graph, 
random sequence is mapped to random graph and fractal 
sequence is mapped to scale free network. Meanwhile, in 
lacasaÆs work there is a linear relationship between the 
degree distribution exponent of visibility graph vertices and 
Hurst exponent of fractional Brownian motion which 
generate the visibility graph [21]. For some stochastic 
process, the fractal property has tight relationship [22-23]. 
The visibility graph theory has been applied in many fields, 
such as the analysis of Chinese macro economy time series 
in seasons [24], the test of wide speed in central Argentina 
[25] and the dynamics of humanÆs heart  ect [26]. Although 
the visibility graph theory is based on the single variable 
time series and in this sense the research on the degree 
distribution cannot provide us more information, however, it 
is still useful for numerical analysis of time series. 
 As the research on visibility graph going deeper and 
deeper, Luque et al. [27] proposed Horizontal Visibility 
Graph (HVG) model. HVG is an improvement of VG, for 
the same time series, its HVG is the subgraph of its VG. 
Although the degree distributions of HVGs generated from 
chaos time series and correlated time series are all 
exponential distribution. However, the distribution values are 
different. When the value is less than ln(1.5), the HVG 
describe the chaos series, while when the value is larger than 
ln(1.5), the HVG describe the correlated random series, 
specially, when the distribution exponent is equal to ln(1.5), 
the HVG describe random series with independent 
identically distributed variable.  All the topological 
properties of HVG generated from fractional Brownian 
motion are depended on Hurst exponent: As the increasing of 
Hurst exponent, the absolute value of the degree distribution 
exponent of HVG is increasing, meanwhile, the clustering 
2015 7th International Conference on Intelligent Human-Machine Systems and Cybernetics
978-1-4799-8646-0/15 $31.00 ⌐ 2015 IEEE
DOI 10.1109/IHMSC.2015.238
308
2015 7th International Conference on Intelligent Human-Machine Systems and Cybernetics
978-1-4799-8646-0/15 $31.00 ⌐ 2015 IEEE
DOI 10.1109/IHMSC.2015.238
311
Authorized licensed use limited to: INTERNATIONAL INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY. Downloaded on February 07,2026 at 19:07:10 UTC from IEEE Xplore.  Restrictions apply. 
--- Page 2 ---
Error reading Time_Series_Analysis_Based_on_Visibility_Graph_Theory.pdf: 'charmap' codec can't encode character '\u2212' in position 1142: character maps to <undefined>

==================================================

